字幕編輯：南昌小冰影音科技     QQ：1010607090
本字幕根據網上已有字幕編輯及調整而來
不得用于商業用途，否則后果自負
片名：《偷天密碼》 或 《親密如賊》
俄國人以為他們可以主宰世界了
尤其是這些人
什么  沒有一輛車
像我們做生意的還是匿名比較好
我喜歡要一輛車
好的
All right.
我知道，我知道
- (Screaming) - I know, I know, I know.
一支槍 對任何人不是威脅，除了你
A gun... It's dangerous for no one except you.
你知道  我要什么   不是嗎
You know what I want, don't you?
是的
Yes.
你在浪費時間 跟我玩
You're wasting time. Don't fuck with me!
打開它 打開它
Open it. Open it!
打開它
Open it!
把我要的東西給我
Give me what I want.
我不明白 我沒有你要的東西
I don't understand, I don't have anything else.
如果有個人給你所有的錢    我會接受的
If the man's offering you all that money, I'd take it.
如果我需要財務建議時  我會打電話給我的經紀
When I need financial advice, I'll call my broker.
我只是說說而已  隨你怎么說
- I'm just saying, is all. - Whatever.
衣服脫下來  脫下來
Take off your coat. Take off your coat!
有多難呢    對不起    打擾一下
- Now, how hard was that? - Excuse me.
先生，我以為我告訴...
Mister, I thought I told...
什么
What the?...
(Screaming)
閃開 大家都趴下
Go, go! Move! Everybody down!
走開
Move! Move!
閃開
Move!
閃
閃開
Go, go, go!
快點 閃開
Suspect white or Hispanic male. Wearing a reflective vest.
發現疑犯 西班牙男子 穿一反光上衣
他在車頂上      所有 Vernon Jackson 單位注意
He's on top of the cars. All units at Vernon Jackson.
大家都蹲下，大家都蹲下
- Everybody down! Stay down! - (Screaming)
在另一頭
Other end!
大家趴下 快 快
Everybody down! Keep moving! Keep moving!
快點 快點 大家趴下
Move, move! Everybody down! Face down on the platform!
快點 趴下 大家都離開火車
Come on, face down! Everybody off the train!
快點 趴下 下來
Come on, face down! Get down!(Shouting)
長官 快點
- Officer... - Move!
大家快點 快點下來
Come on, guys, get down!
下來 下來
Get your ass down! Get down!
下來 搜查火車
Get down! Search the tracks!
他跑到隧道里去了 檢查隧道 檢查車頂
He went down the tunnel? Check the tunnel, check the roof.
大家快點 趴在地上
Come on, people! Face down on the ground now!
他跳到車頂上去了
(Man) He jumped! He was on the roof!
火車已經關閉了 沒人可以上去
(Policeman) This train is closed. Nobody gets on.
先生 冷靜點
Sir, I need you to calm down.
讓大家離開
Get these people moving.
就停在這兒
Stop right there.
膽子可真不小啊
The punk's got balls...
但是看不太清楚
but no positive identification.
不 啊    月臺另一邊還有外一個攝像頭
No... huh, there's another camera pointing at the platform.
麥克 停
Michaels, stop it right there.
你看到了嗎
You see what I see?
也許 就是他 警長
- Maybe. - That's him, Lieutenant.
誰
That's who?
你什么時候當偵探了 麥克
How long have you been a detective, Micheals?
11個月以前
11 months, sir.
我在刑偵科工作22年了
I'm 22 years in robbery and homicide.
盜賊中有一類叫 藝術品大盜
One of your subcategories of robbery is art theft.
蘋果有很多種類,盜匪也一樣
There's a lot of that in the Apple.
在紐約有很多那樣的人 你注意到了嗎 麥克
Are you aware of that, Michaels?
是的 我不像你
- I guess so, yeah. - I wasn't.
我是你這么大的時候  我就可以處理殺人案件了
When I was your age, I was happy with regular murder and mayhem.
韋伯警長有出色的表現
Lieutenant Weber minored in art history at Fordham.
哦
Oh.
不管怎么樣 他們叫我畢卡索警長
Anyway, the Chief starts calling me Lieutenant Picasso...
讓我負責一切偷竊案
and puts me in charge every time there is the theft...
和盡可能多的犯罪案件
of as much as an Etch-A-Sketch.
20多年來 我都能將他們處理的漂漂亮亮的
Two decades, I've been putting 'em all away.
但是除了他
Everybody but him, Keith Ripley.
他是我唯一沒有制服的
Keith  Ripley
He's the best there is. Howdy, Keith.
你真是一個壞小子
You've been bad boy.
也許我可以給你15  不
- Perhaps I could give you 15. - No.
那不可能
That is not possible.
少于100我可不干
I wouldn't take less than 100.
我只是說說而已
I'm just saying, is all.
你...
You...
你不介意我借用一下吧
Mind if I borrow this?
- 我也許想用一下它 - 嗯
- Well, I may have wanted to use it. - Mm.
你的給我拿來
But yours will do.
把我的槍放下
Will you please put down my gun?
加布里 有件情你應該注意一下了
There's one thing you should be aware of, Gabriel
你喜歡自己還是馬丁
or do you prefer yourself or Martin?
警察是不會因為你帶槍而逮捕你的
The police cannot arrest you for armed robbery
如果你的槍沒上膛的話
if your gun isn't loaded.
你的意思是...
Your point?
你以為我會帶上一把上好膛的槍出來走嗎
You think I'd walk around with a loaded shotgun?
我們試試吧 （扣槍聲）
- Let's see. - (Gun clicks)
你早就應該試一下的 為什么
- You could have checked. - Why?
你已經擁有了我的鉆石 我的槍 我的錢
You have my diamonds, my score, my money.
盡情享受吧 很高興認識你們二位 再見
Enjoy. Nice meeting you both. Bye.
隨便說一下 我準備開口要125
By the way, I was going to ask for 125.
我只是說說
I'm just saying, is all.
站住 加布里  為什么
- Gabriel, stay. - Why?
你還想要什么 先殺了我
What else do you want? You gonna shoot me now?
鑒于鉆石是你偷來的
Well, in as much as you did steal the diamonds
我想只有讓你一份 分享成果才算公平嘛
I figure it's only fair to share the proceeds with you.
那我是應該感謝你的慷慨和大方了
So to what do I owe this act of generosity?
我有一個事情要跟你討論
I have a proposition I wish to discuss with you.
那么...
So...
你怎么知道我會來
how did you know I would come here
又怎么知道我的名字
as well as my name?
這只是事情的一部分
It's part of the proposition...
哦 該死
Oh, shit!
快
Come on
- 好吧  - 放輕松點 放輕松點
- All right  - take it easy, take it easy.
尼基要拿回他的錢
Nicky would like his money.
問他 真他媽的謝謝你
- Ask him. - Thank you.
這是你跟他們的事 與我無關
This is between you and them. Got nothing to do with me.
現在一切都清楚了
Everything does now.
你應該感到高興 尼基等你都不耐煩了
Call this interest. Nicky is tired of waiting for you.
俄語
(Speaks Russian)
你會得到報應的
You must have very bad karma.
我一點都不相信佛家這套 還是說我們那個事情吧
I actually don't believe in it. Still, about this propos...
不不不不 你瘋了
No, no, no, no! You're totally out of your mind.
晚安
Good night.
嘿  什么事
- Hey. - What?
這是你的報酬
Here's your karma.
另外一個信封里是什么  你開了就知道了
- What was in the other envelope? - Your cut.
現在你拿到的是我的那份
Now you've got mine.
隨你怎么說
Whatever.
考慮考慮吧 好的
- Think about it. - Yeah, sure, yeah.
嗯
Hmm.
你現在想要什么
Now... what do you want?
一個拍檔
A partner.
你覺得我在火車上干什么
What'd you think I was doing on that train?
我一直在看著你
- I was watching you work. - Hm.
從你一出現 我就開始關注著你
I've been your shadow ever since you got to town.
為什么你在我的小鎮地鐵里搶劫
So why were you in my town robbing subways?
邁阿密正是颶風盛行 我不喜歡
It's hurricane season in Miami. I don't like hurricanes.
還是你不喜歡回到安哥拉
Or you didn't feel like going back to Angola.
結束了
It's over.
學到教訓了
Lesson learned
看...
Look...
加布里 馬丁是明星
Gabriel Martin is a rock star.
為什么你那天晚上在地鐵拿著槍公開搶劫
So why were you holding open-mike night on the subway...
弄他個1O幾萬什么的
for a lousy 100 grand?
兩個理由
Two reasons...
是的 邁阿密變得越來越熱了
Yes, Miami was getting too hot.
也許這與你有關
And perhaps you can relate to this.
有時候是這樣
Sometimes...
有時候你得感到緊迫點
Sometimes you just need to feel the rush.
來杯果汁
The juice.
好
Yeah.
你明白我的意思
You know what I mean.
昨天 你拿下了兩個珠寶
Yesterday, you took down two jewelers...
從羅曼那里
for a few stones from Romanov's.
我就只是要羅曼的
My idea is Romanov's itself.
請
(Sniggers) Please...
具體來說 藝術品法貝格彩蛋值2000萬美元
Specifically, two Faberg eggs worth 20 million dollars...
每個人
Each.
這需要兩個人合作
It's a two-man job.
夠吸引人的吧
Do I have your attention?
在這里等著
Wait here.
我聽說他們喜歡現金 還有你的初次表現
I hear they prefer cash... or your first-born.
為什么不看看這個
Why don't you try The Standard instead?
嫉妒？
Jealous?
嫉妒誰啊
Of who?
神秘大盜
The mystery bandit.
我想我不是那種類型的人
I'm afraid that type of thing is not my style.
哦 我認為你這個人還挺威風挺有膽量的
Well, I think this guy's got panache... guts.
跟那個穿過地鐵的人樣子很像 至少體型很像
And a passing resemblance, at least in body type.
你不一定要通過搶劫地鐵來表現威風
Well, you don't have to rob trains to have panache.
或者膽量 但是你得承認那種事情能讓你馬上被人記住
Or guts... but you've gotta admit that kind of thing immediately brands you.
俄語
(Speaks Russian)
我請客 老是看到你讀斯拉夫報紙
My treat... too painful watching you attempt to read Cyrillic.
不不不不 我只是 啊 看看圖片
Oh, no, no, no... I was just... huh, looking at the picture.
所以你就是在嫉妒了
So you are jealous.
是的 被你看出來了 真的
Yes... you got me there. Absolutely.
我得去那里了 給我老板帶中國菜
I've gotta get this... Chinese food to my boss...
哦 嗯
so, um...
回見
some other time.
什么時候 我打你的電話？
- When, some other time? - I'll call you.
但是你沒有我的電話號碼 不知道我的名字和別的
But you don't have my number or know my name or anything.
我覺得那不會是個問題
I guess that could be a problem.
Ripley
(Ripley)
加布里
Gabriel.
哦 該死 你跟他一起的嗎
- Oh, shit! - Are you with him?
我不知道 我應該那樣嗎 還是
I don't know. Should I? More or less.
啊 是的 我跟他一起的
Ahh... yes, I am.
你想要什么
What'd you want?
我就不能給我的教女買個生日禮物嗎
Can't I bring my goddaughter a birthday present?
我的生日是上個月
My birthday was last month.
兩個星期前 對不起我送晚了
It was two weeks ago and I'm sorry it's late.
阿歷克斯 只是一份禮物 沒什么的
Alex, it's just a present. No strings.
不需要了 謝謝
No thanks.
哦 很高興遇到了你 加布里
Well, it was nice to have almost met you, Gabriel.
加比 加比
- Gaby. - Gaby.
真是遺憾啊 老是被人控制著
It's a shame you don't keep a higher class of company.
別在意她   那該在意什么呢
- Don't even think about it. - Think about what?
你給我離她遠點 要不然我會要了你的命的 我是說真的
You go anywhere near her. I'll rip your heart out. I mean it.
會要了你的命吧 她好像不怎么喜歡你
It looks like it's your heart, she's not so fond of.
我警告過你了啊 走吧
You were warned. Let's go.
我記得你說過目標是羅曼家
(Gabriel) I thought you said the target was Romanov's.
- 這只是一個調查    - 一個調查?
- This is research.    - Research?
哦, 哇哦!
Oh, wow!
他們太顯眼了
They're absolutely stunning.
太顯眼了
(Ripley) They are.
在1885年到1916年
Between 1885 and 1916...
法貝格為女皇制作了50顆復活節彩蛋
Faberg produced 50 of these Easter eggs for the Empress...
她的皇家兒媳 卓愛麗娜 阿歷克桑德拉
and her daughter-in-law, the Czarina Alexandra.
我要記下來嗎?
Should I take notes?
要作小測試的嗎?
Will there be a quiz?
沒有測試 但會是一個考驗
No quiz but there will be a test.
好 這些彩蛋都是用貴重金屬和珠寶做成的
Okay... the Faberg are all made of precious metals and fine jewels.
- 每一件都是實際上獨一無二的珍品  - 的確
- Every one a unique masterpiece.  - Indeed.
大部分都陳列在克里姆林宮
Most are on display in the Kremlin.
其他的被收藏家或者收藏館收藏了 或者遺失了
The rest in private collections, museums... or lost.
這樣的情青況下 只有羅曼家有了
In this case, at Romanov's.
誰是你的買家
Who is your buyer?
你不會想知道的
You don't want to know.
哦 我要偷價值4000萬美元的彩蛋 當然要知道買家是誰了
Oh, I'm stealing 40 million dollars worth of eggs so I want to know.
我也想知道為什么這些奇特的彩蛋
I also want to know why these particular eggs...
可以值4000萬美金
are even worth 40 million dollars.
因為沒有人知道它們在哪里
Because no one knows they exist.
哦
Oh.
- 所以就叫做神秘的蛋  - 嗯
- The so-called mystery eggs?  - Mm-hm.
是的 我當時也聽說了很多謠言 想那只是個神話罷了
Yeah, I've heard rumours, but I thought it was just a myth.
去年 彩蛋現身了    在羅曼家
Last year, they turned up...    at Romanov's.
你是怎么知道的
So how do you know this?
我當時和一個叫維克多 克羅勒克的拍檔一起 就是阿歷克斯的父親
I was partners with a man named Victor Korolenko... Alex's father.
他和俄方有緊密的聯系
He was in tight with the Russians.
俄方知道的 他也知道
What they knew, he knew.
那為什么你不跟他合作這件事呢
So, why aren't you pulling this job with him?
現在他不在了
Let's just say he's no longer around.
不說他了
Leave it at that.
他都走了
He's gone.
而剛好你來了
You're here.
現在 我們要分頭行動了
Now we just have to deliver.
Ripley  嗯
- Ripley... - Hmm?
為什么
Why?
為什么要把你自己的自由做賭注
Why risk your freedom at all?
你令人難以理解
This will not be anything close to easy.
現在你又不在監獄里
You are not in jail in the present.
你不舒服嗎   我從來沒有舒服過
- Are you not comfortable? - I'm never comfortable.
有些人天生就會做音樂
Some people were born to compose music.
有些人會分離原子
Others to split the atom.
而我是生來就會偷東西
I was born to steal shit.
伸出你的手來
Hold out your hand.
手？
Hand?
我和維克多做拍檔時他送了這枚硬幣給我
That coin was given to me by Victor when we became partners.
它在俄語中是有含義的
The coin represents a Russian phrase.
翻譯過來就是, 賊的世界
"Vorovoslky mlr". Loosely translated, thieves' world.
維克多屬于它
Victor belonged to it.
現在
Now...
你屬于它
you belong to it.
嘿
Psst... Hey!
你誤會了   Ripley 跟我只是生意關系
You misunderstand.   Ripley's just... huh, business.
這個是 嗯
This is... huh...
潛行追蹤？
Stalking?
呃 如果你早就給我號碼的話 我就會先打給你了
Well... if you had given me your number, I would have called first.
太蹩腳的猜想了
Those are two very flawed assumptions.
你有花瓶嗎
Do you have a vase?
我從路邊的圣壇采的
I just took these from a roadside shrine...
我想它們需要一點水
and I think they need some, huh... water.
啊
Huh...
我可以用那個嗎？ 可以
- May I use that... huh, thing over there? - Sure...
我發現了一個  俄羅斯夜總會   就在下面的那個街區
I... I've noticed this... huh, Russian nightclub, down the block, huh...
好像叫 Riga Rose
Riga Rose or something like that.
何不下班后到那里聚聚
Why don't we meet there after work?
我很忙
I'm busy.
我等你   我不會去的
- I'll wait. - I won't show.
我還是會等你的
I'll take my chances.
再見 阿歷克桑德拉
Do svldanja, Alexandra.
調查  Keith  Ripley  93年 布魯克林博物館
Research. Keith Ripley. '93, the Brooklyn Museum.
94年 鉆石區倉庫 95年...
'94, the Diamond District Warehouse and then in '95...
麥克 我太熟悉 Ripley 的生平事跡了
I'm very familiar with Ripley's life story, Michaels.
事實上 我抓過他兩次
In fact, I busted him twice.
因為律師辯護得力  兩次都讓他逃了
Both times he walked because of good lawyering.
的確  我想何不改變策略
Exactly, so I thought why not swing for the fences?
一個殺人案  死者 維克多
Murder one, Victor Korolenko.
想想   布萊特海岸蒸汽浴室   忘記它吧   那里沒有
Thinkin ' of the Brighton Beach steam bath? Forget it. There was no...
沒有尸體     但是我們可用法醫驗證     沒有目擊者
- No body. But we've got a ton of forensics. - And no witnesses.
沒有人敢出來作證
Nobody there admitted to seeing a thing.
我差點能說服 維克多 接受證人保護
I was this close to convincing Korolenko to take witness protection,
來指控 Ripley
in exchange for giving up Ripley.
但是 Ripley 先行了一步
But Ripley got to him first.
我又一次功虧一簣了
I can't prove it.
對 好吧 我明白了
Right, okay. I see, I see... okay.
不 麥克
No... what you don't see, Michaels,
你不明白的是為什么 Ripley 會卷入犯罪里
is why Ripley got involved in a small-time caper,
比如在地鐵里搶劫鉆石還能逃走
like grabbin ' a few diamonds off of some couriers on a subway.
我也不明白
And neither did I.
直到我聽了一個荷蘭人的陳述
Until I read the Dutch guy's statement.
這些鉆石來自于羅曼家
Those diamonds came from Romanov's.
你的意思是 Ripley 和他的新搭檔計劃對羅曼家動手
You mean Ripley and his new partner are planning to take down Romanov's?
呃 來 像那樣的事情是不會發生的
Ah... come on. Like that could ever happen.
他還不只會對羅曼家下手呢
Not even Ripley could take down a place like that.
要不我們打個賭
Wanna bet?
- Hi. - Hi.
你對這個地方很熟   我沒有這樣說
- You know this place very well. - I never said I didn't.
還是說實話吧 你本不知道這家夜總會的
Let's face it, you didn't see the nightclub.
你看到了我傳真機上的扉頁 然后就順嘴說了
You saw the flyer in the fax and then you made an assumption.
是的 罪過 我確實是這么干的
Yeah. Guilty. So I did.
沒有想過要編造什么 特別是來這里
Never assume anything, especially down here.
真神秘
- How mysterious.
- 什么？    - 真神秘
- What?     - How mysterious.
我可以請你喝一杯嗎  我不喝酒的
- Can I buy you a drink? - I don't drink.
那你來干什么
Another assumption.
跳舞嗎
You wanna dance?
好吧
Yeah.
我不怕出洋相 為什么不跳呢
I'm willing to make a fool of myself. Why not?
（俄語）這兒
(Alex speaks Russian) Here.
給他 謝謝
- And for him. - Thank you.
謝謝
Thanks.
我以為每個俄國人都喝酒的呢
I thought all Russians drank.
酒，翻譯過來是 喝了以后容易犯事的飲料
Translation, we're a race of suicidal alcoholics.
不 我不是那個意思 不是
No... I didn't mean that. No.
實際上 事實是這樣的 干杯
Actually, we are. Cheers.
干杯 干杯
- Nastravila? - Nastravise
干杯 嗯
Nastravise? Mm'mm
為律師做事是怎么樣的
So... how is it... working for the lawyer?
嗯 我就是一個律師
- Huh... I'm a lawyer, too, you know. - Oh.
也許我不會說話了 因為我說的都是錯的
Maybe I won't say another word, because everthing I say is wrong.
你不試試 你怎能知道  那倒是
- Well, you don't know until you try. - True.
還有 我父親不讓我做律師
Besides, my father warned me about being a lawyer.
他要我嘗試 要對自己的一生保持忠誠
He told me I should try and do something honest with my life.
假如他還能知道的話
As if he would know.
你父親和 Ripley 很親密對吧
Your father and Ripley, they were close, right?
以前是
Once upon a time.
Ripley 告訴過你吧 我父親過世了
I'm sure Ripley told you. My father's dead.
現在 Ripley 要照顧我
Now Ripley likes to try to take care of me.
還債  之類的事青
Pay for stuff. That kind of thing.
當然 他至少可以這樣做
Of course, it's the least he can do.
對不起 我不是要打探什么
Sorry. I don't mean to pry.
可是 你確實是在打探啊
Yes, you do.
這是你的想法
Now who is making assumptions?
不 加比 我沒有想什么
No, Gaby. I'm not assuming a thing.
你想了解 Ripley ?
You wanna know about Ripley?
離他遠點
Stay away.
混蛋
You son of a bitch!
哦 你忘了這個
Well... you dropped these...
我好心把它給你送回來了
and I am a gentleman bringing them back to you.
噢 噢
Uh-huh.
不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no!
不
No!
該死的 大哥 你想干什么呀
Shit, man! What do you want?
我告訴過你讓你離她遠點
I told you to leave her alone.
我下次不會再警告你了
I'm not gonna tell you again.
穿好衣服 我先下樓
Get dressed. I'll be downstairs.
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
太棒了
Fascinating.
在設計完成以前 你可以開始你的準備工作了
You could start a whole new trend in interior design.
這些是什么  看起來像什么？
- What are these? - What do they look like?
警察證？
Police IDs?
今晚在羅曼家有一個招待會 為NYPD辦的
There's a reception at Romanov's tonight, honouring the NYPD.
我們的邀請函也剛收到了
And our invitation's just arrived.
今晚我們要扮警察
A cop for the night.
還可以吃到炸面圈
And all the doughnuts you can eat.
期間 我要你進入到干洗店去
Meanwhile, however, Ineed you to go to the dry-cleaners.
先生 為什么你自己不去取你干洗好的衣服呢
Why don't you go and pick up your dry-cleaning yourself, sir?
誰說的要去“取”
Who said anything about picking up?
你自己掉下的
You're dropping off.
越南語
(Speaks Vietnamese)
手機
Cellphone, please.
好了，瑟吉夫，正如美國人所說的
我們有網路要做
你好 長官 先生
- Commissioner Rawls. - Gentlemen.
副長官 莫雷利
Deputy Commissioner Morelli.
很高興見到你
Such a pleasure having you here.
我帶你參觀參觀
May we give you gentlemen the grand tour?
羅曼的秘密 可以這么說
- The secrets of Romanov? - You might say so.
謝謝 榮幸之極 請
- Thank you. We're honored. - Please.
這些警衛 都是FBI的警察
(Ripley) The guards, all FSB secret police.
每道門 每塊玻璃和線路都有報警裝置
Every door, every inch of glass wired and alarmed.
所以一只鳥也飛不進來的
So even if a bird flies in here, you know about it.
Topkapi.
Rififi.
不 鳥可以飛到博物館還可以挺在電線上
No, the bird flew into the museum, landed on the wire...
線路已經鋪好了 那是在電影通天大盜里
and set off the alarm in Topkapi.
你是一個電影愛好者
You're a cineaste.
實際上 我只看搶劫盜竊這一類的片子
Actually, I only see heist movies.
從一只鳥 飛到博物館然后又逃出來得到的經驗
Well, the lesson to take away from the bird flying into the museum...
就是無論你如何規劃 總是要臨時發揮的
is no matter how well you planned, always be ready to improvise...
因為 我向你保證 事情有時要出錯的
because, I guarantee you, something's gonna go wrong.
我盡量避免 嗯
- I'd prefer to avoid that. - Uh-huh.
監視系統有多精密？
How comprehensive is the surveillance system?
讓我看看
Let's take a look.
俄語
(Speaks Russian)
- 每個電梯都要通行卡   - 每道門也是一樣
- Smart card for the elevator.   - And all the doors.
這邊 你走先
This way. After you.
我們走吧
We're on.
見到你真好 讓我介紹一下
Good to see you, old friend. Let me introduce you.
韋伯警長 恕我冒昧啊
Lieutenant Weber, I presume.
你要知道 Ripley  假冒警察可是嚴重的犯罪
You know, Ripley, identity theft is a serious crime.
- 是相當令人難堪的事情   -真的？
- And quite an embarrassing one in this case.   - Really?
你意識到有多羞恥嗎
Do you realise how ashamed I felt...
告訴門口那些可愛的女士們我是假冒的警察
telling that nice lady at the door that I was still a lieutenant?
我的意思是說以我這樣的年紀
I mean at my age?
或者說以你這樣的年紀
Or should I say at your age?
我不是開玩笑
I'm not amused.
你在這里干什么?
What are you doing here?
你被邀請?
And why did you appropriate my invitation?
我好像一無所知
As if I didn't know.
我為我的托辭道歉
I apologise for the subterfuge.
我只是想帶我的朋友來看看 這有什么好東西
I just wanted to show my friend here some of the finer things in life.
如果你因為我們假扮警察要逮捕我們 那就請便吧
If you want to arrest us for impersonating police officers, go right ahead.
我可以保證我的律師會在兩個小時候替我們開脫的
I'm sure my lawyer will have us out in two hours.
那將會是令人愉快的兩個小時 把你的手放下來
It'd be a delightful two hours. Get your hands down.
那就不知道你該怎么向你的上司解釋了
Then there's all that explaining you'd have to do to your superiors.
那該是多么尷尬的事情啊
Now that would be an embarrassment.
聲名狼藉的賊卻因為假扮成你而得到認可
Notorious thief gaining admittance pretending to be you.
韋伯 你的工作很出色嘛
Great police work, Weber.
我們應該在事情結束以后到警局談談
We should discuss my police work when this is all over.
嗯
Hmm.
你這位朋友是誰   喬斯達桑
- Who's your sidekick? - Jules Dassin.
很高興見到你 喬斯 我很喜歡看你的電影
Good to meet you, Jules. I love your movies.
祝你們玩得開心 先生們
Enjoy the party, gents.
小心點
While it lasts.
好 你現在可以告訴我這一切都是怎么回事嗎？
Now... do you mind telling me what that was all about?
只是一個警察罷了 真的 別開玩笑了
- Just a cop. - Really? No kidding.
我們就從這個地方開始 我們要拿下這個地方
We have been made in the very place we are supposed to take down.
準確地說 你是怎么出獄的
Exactly how do you stay out of jail?
除非你跟這個韋伯是一伙的 你們共同設計要陷害我
Unless, of course, you and this Weber are partners trying to set me up.
是嗎  Ripley ？
Are you, Ripley?
我們走
Here we go.
來呀 快點
Come on. Move your damn ass!
韋伯不知道我們來這里干什么
Weber has no idea what we're here for.
他當然知道
Of course he does.
他不知道我們什么時候開始 也不知道我們用什么方式
He doesn't know when and he doesn't know how.
還有 他不知道彩蛋的事
And, no, he doesn't know about the eggs.
這里 沒有一個人知道
No one does. Here.
避開韋伯最好的辦法
The best way to neutralise Weber...
就是在忙亂中轉移他的注意力
is to fuel his obsession with busting me.
他在那樣的情況下 根本不會像警察那樣思考了
He's so blinded by it, he no longer thinks like a cop.
相信我
Trust me.
要怎么才能讓我相信你 啊
Give me a good reason to, huh?
我已經給了你4000萬這個好理由了
I already gave you 40 million good reasons. Here.
現在你們已經看到了大家所看的 是時候讓你們大飽眼福了
Now you've seen what the public sees, it's time for the real treat.
那是 當然 你們要保證不會回來搶我們
That is, of course, as long as you promise not to come back and rob us.
我不會記錄下來的
I guess I won't take any notes, then.
我們的主要地下室
Our main vault. (Clicks fingers)
螺旋探測儀
Gregor dlsarm the motlon detectors...
跟所有的通信設備相連
Even with the knowledge of all protocols,
真是堅不可摧
it is absolutely impregnable.
聲感器會檢查我們的主腦安全 謝爾蓋耶夫 鮑利斯
The voice sensors ask our head of security, Boris Sergeev,
實現記錄好的文字 隨機抽取設置
a random set of pre-recorded words.
但這只是程式的一半
But this is only half the process.
生物測定式手印感測器
We also have a biometric handprint sensor.
既然謝爾蓋耶夫先生和我是唯有的兩位通關者
Since Mr. Sergeev and I are the only ones who have clearance,
那就由我們兩個來打開地下室吧
we must both be present to open the vaults.
一旦我開啟生物測定式手印感測器
Once I activate the biometric handprint sensor,
它就會啟動聲感器
he must activate the voice sensor.
這樣的話我們兩個都不能從彼此那里偷到任何東西
This way neither of us can steal from the other.
你最好是祈禱謝爾蓋耶夫先生有健康的身體
Well, you better hope Mr. Sergeev stays healthy.
我也必須保持健康的身體
(Zykov) I must stay healthy as well!
漢堡包 漢堡包
- (Compuuter) Hamburger. - Hamburger.
大蘋果  大蘋果
- Blg Apple. - Big Apple.
耶穌 耶穌
Jesus Christ.
時間一過地下室的門會自動重啟
(Zykov) The vault door automatlcally resets on the hour...
那個時候感應器必須反向啟動
at which polnt the sensor must be actlvated in reverse...
所有的人做好準備  別被關在里面了
All In all gentlemen best not to get locked Inslde
我說得是不是聽起來很容易
Well, did I say it was gonna be easy?
不 但是你并沒有說不可能
No, but you didn't say it would be impossible either.
防彈玻璃
(Zykov) Armoured glass...
要想一次性打開它 得花半個小時
It would take half an hour to break through just one case.
但是我想只要有人花上半秒鐘就會知道錯了
But, I'm afraid, whoever tried wouldn't even have half a second...
超聲波探測儀會自動將其鎖在里面
because an ultrasonic motion detector would automatically lock him in...
然后觸發報警器
and trigger the alarm.
安保人員想要進入也并非易事
Contalnment securlty gentlemen Gettlng in is highly improbable...
老實說 想要出來也是不可能的
But gettlng out is frankly imposslble.
那道門通向哪里?
Where does that door lead to?
通向我們的內室 那里藏了我們最寶貴的東西
(Zykov) To our inner vault which contalns our most precious items...
很遺憾 但是出于安全需要
I'm sorry but security prevents me...
我不能帶你們到那里去 即使你們是我尊貴的客人
from taking even this distinguished group in there.
現在我們要返回接待廳了 但是在回去之前
Now we'll proceed back to the reception, but before we do...
我還是要再次感謝你們
I'd like to, once again, thank you both...
感謝你們去年來對我的關照
for your generosity this last year in helping set up our business.
謝謝 還有你們的善意募捐
And thank you very much for the donatlon of that chopper.
歡迎你們的光臨
(Zykov) You're quite welcome.
我們走 我們可以做到的 加布里
- Let's go. - We can do this, Gabriel.
不 完全不可能的
No... Absolutely not.
- 我很高興 但是我要走了  拜拜      - 等一下，等一下
- It was a pleasure. Goodbye.      - Wait a minute. Wait.
我們現在哪兒也不去
We're not going any where yet.
如果zykov發現了那個攝像頭 他就會知道我們的事
If Zykov finds that camera, he's gonna know what it is.
他們會改變所有的裝備的
They'll change all the protocols.
你到底明不明白啊 我沒有興趣
Which part of "I don't give a shit" do you not understand?
俄語
(Speaks Russian)
Sorry. Let me just...
不好意思 讓我
- I'll handle it. - No, no, no.
我來處理 不不不
- Please, please. Allow me. - I'm absolutely okay.
讓我來 我很好
I apologise, sir.
我向你道歉
搞什么
What the fuck?
韋伯探長 我是 Hal Donley 特工 專責此次行動
Detective Weber, I'm Hal Donley, special agent in charge of this op.
你正在負責調查的那個嫌疑犯
You're conducting an investigation of a potential theft...
正從羅曼珠寶店出來
that you assume is going down at Romanov Jewelers.
嫌疑  才怪
Assume, my ass.
我知道他們被記錄在案 我也知道他們就要成功逃脫了
I know it's going down and I know who's pulling it off.
除了我要詢問你是否要呼叫你的手下
Except we're asking you to call off your dogs.
有一些其他重要的事要做
There are other matters that take precedence.
有什么要做的事
What could possibly take precedence...
比抓住一個鉆石盜竊犯更重要
over the potential theft of millions of dollars in diamonds...
他們化裝成NYPD還從珠寶店大搖大擺的出來
from a company that donates tons of money and equipment to the NYPD?
瓦倫丁?
Valentin?
Vitaly Zykov 前蘇聯時代
Vitaly Zykov, in the old Soviet days,
是一個叫 Dimitri Kuzin 的團伙老板  的  得力助手
was the right-hand man to a party boss named Dimitri Kuzin.
Kuzin 在美國設立這個虛假而獨立  的  俄羅斯皇家鉆石中心
Kuzin set up a supposedly independent Russian diamond centre in America.
羅曼的
Romanov's...
但是鉆石．我對他一無所知
But diamonds... they're not all that he's shipping over here.
他竊取俄羅斯國寶已久,   探員
He's ripping off the Russian Treasury, Detective.
金，首飾，藝術品
Gold, gems, artworks.
各位，你們覺得 羅曼 的錢由那來？
Gentlemen, where do you think Romanov's got the money...
給你們的部門送直升機, 現在又送車？
to buy your department a helicopter and now police cars?
錢是從鉆石貿易得來的嗎？
From retail diamond sales?
那他們為什么那樣做？ 這是個嚴重問題嗎？
- So why are they doing this? - Is that a serious question?
所以 NYPD 不要管他
So the NYPD will leave them alone.
這才是正道
That's their mindset.
我們需要 放長線 吊大魚
We need more time to build our mutual cases.
這是為什么我們不作其他調查的原因
That's why we can't have any other investigations...
以免驚動了 Zykov
potentially alerting Zykov.
警長
Lieutenant...
停止調查
shut it down.
各位，解散
- Gentlemen. - Commissioner...
為免你覺得比我們聰明
Just in case you think you're smarter than us,
而暗中繼續進行調查
decide to continue this investigation on a down and low,
算了吧
forget it.
這件事比你想像的大，你明白了嗎？
This is bigger than you and your ego. Do you get it?
我明白了
I get it.
你說什么？  沒什么，一切照舊
- What did the feds have to say? - Nothing. Everything's still a go.
第一步要越過保安攝像頭
(Ripley) The first order of business is to bypass the security cameras.
如果我們能進入監控系統
(Martin) If we can gain access into the surveillance system,
我們可以換上預先錄制好的重復影像
we can replace the light feed with a continuous loop of study shots...
而不被攝入保安攝錄機
with no face inside.
還有聲波識別器
That still leaves the voice sensors,
指紋和掃描器，動作探測器
the fingerprints, the motion detectors,
從沒見過這樣的閥門
the meanest-looking vault door I have ever seen in my life.
內部閥門  瑞士制   三尺厚
(Ripley) The inner vault door, Swiss-made, 3 feet thick,
連彈簧驅動重鎖閂
with spring-driven relocking bolts.
如果你把鎖撞開，其它的馬上上鎖
If you punch out the lock, they block retraction...
即使知道組合也打不開
so that you couldn't open it even if you knew the combination.
亞伯拉罕．林肯
(Sergev) Abraham Lincoln.
（電腦發音）百老匯 百老匯
- (Computer) Broadway. - Broadway.
30 組預錄音詞語．一星期，我們要所有集齊
30 pre-recorded words. One week, we've got them all.
是，我們來維修的
Yes, we're going to be doing some maintenance work...
請問是MTA公司嗎？
Dan McWilliams, MTA.
下周在連接你的地下室的隧道內
in the subway adjacent to your basement next week.
要在夜間工作，不想鉆具的噪音打擾到你們
We'll be working nights and didn't want the drilling to alarm you.
超音波轉換器放這里
You place an ultrasonic transducer here,
在特定的頻普上廣播傳送
broadcasting at the exact operating frequency of the transmitter...
反射頻率到這個裝置
and it bounces back the frequency to the unit.
基本的公式
At least in theory.
你用過超音波轉換器嗎？
Have you ever used an ultrasonic transducer?
沒有
Nope.
那你能找來一個超音波轉換器嗎？
Can you get an ultrasonic transducer?
朋友，我什么都能找來
I can get anything, my friend.
- 你能通過密碼鍵嗎？    - 這是  如常地  是時間問題
- Can you get past a keypad?    - It is, as always, a question of time.
一次處置一個問題
One tumbler at a time.
這有點難  但可以
It is tight... but possible.
俄語
(Speaking Russian)
是你
You.
是的
Yeah.
是我
Me.
有什么好笑的？
What's so funny?
我討厭中國菜
I hate Chinese food.
我絕對、完全不可能吃的
I absolutely, unequivocally
我從不吃中國菜
irrevocably
厭惡中國菜
loathe Chinese food.
哦...
Oh...
Leonid 我老板非常沉迷中國菜
Leonid, my boss, is addicted to Chinese food.
我聞到也不成
I can't even stand the smell.
我再次完全假設錯誤
Another completely wrong assumption.
不
No.
不是完全
It's not completely...
錯了
wrong.
什么？
What?
喔...
Wow.
- 你偷的   -是的
- You stole this.   - Yes, I did.
- 是的   - 這才是我做的
- Didn't you?    - Yes. That's what I do.
等等
Wait.
現在有個問題
We have a problem.
手鐲？
The bracelet?
我會解決的
I cannot return it.
不，我喜歡
No, I like it.
那你說的是什么問題？
So what could possibly be a problem?
你
You.
- 什么？  - 我
- What?   - Me.
我覺得這不是什么問題
I thought that part was not a problem.
Ripley
(Laughs) And Ripley.
那也不是問題
That part is a problem.
只是 Ripley 這個人我無法信任
Yours and Ripley's is a world I just can't trust.
你父親如何死的？
How did your father die?
中槍
By gunshot.
誰干的
Who did it?
賭博，幾個俄羅斯人干的
He had gambling debts to a Russian gangster named Nicky Petrovich.
- 俄羅斯人想要他的錢   - 問他要錢
- Nicky wants his money.   - Ask him.
這么做不太仗義了
This concept of... huh, vorovosky...
是的 我很熟悉這句話
"Vorovosky mlr", Yes, I'm familiar with it.
但是誰該為此事負責？
Where... where one is responsible for the debts of another one.
嘿 為什么那些人要你爸爸死而讓 Ripley 活著？
Hey, why would they kill your father and let Ripley live?
因為 Ripley 有權  我不知道他是怎么
Because Ripley has... I don't know... how'd you want me to put this?
得到權利的
Earning power.
加比
(Whispers) Gaby...
我不想再參加什么葬禮了
I don't wanna go to any more funerals.
我想跟你在一起 但我不能給你什么承諾
I wanna be with you but I can't promise you that,
而你也不能給我什么承諾 所以
and you can't promise me a thing, so...
也許我們不妨試一試
maybe we shouldn't even try.
哦 是你啊
Oh, you, you, you, you.
上車
Get in.
我知道你不想 我知道你也不會的 但是這樣會傷害她
I know you don't want to, I know you don't mean to, but you will hurt her.
她不能夠受任何傷害
She doesn't need any more of that.
你就一點關系都沒有嗎 我說對了嗎？
None of which you had anything to do with. Am I right?
你有什么要問我的？
Is there something you want to ask me?
是
Yes.
為什么維克多死了而你還活著
Why is Victor dead and you're still walking round?
我敢肯定阿歷克斯告訴了你維克多 實際上就是尼基 皮特魯維奇
I'm sure Alex told you that Victor was in deep to a man named Nicky Petrovich.
她不知道的是尼基要一筆勾銷
What she didn't know, that Nicky was ready to forgive the dept,
維克多接受了這份差事
if Victor pulled a job, this job.
維克多沒有遵守諾言 他為了保護阿歷克斯
- Victor backed out? - He was trying to protect Alex.
跟韋伯做了交易 他要放棄自己的自由
Made a deal with Weber. He was gonna drop the dime on Nicky.
- 和你的    - 和我的
- And you.   - And me.
韋伯為維克多提供了保護
Weber offered Victor witness protection.
讓他和阿歷克斯走 但是阿歷克斯不想走
He and Alex, but Alex didn't want to go.
維克多不能跟她一起走 所以
Victor didn't wanna go without her, so...
他就吃了子彈
he bought a bullet instead.
那么為什么這個還是你的問題呢 你為什么不離開
So why is this still your problem? Why don't you just... leave?
你沒有跟尼基做交易 你大可以走開啊
You don't make a deal with Nicky for the throw of it and then walk away.
事情還是沒有完  尼基想要那些彩蛋
There's no statute of limitations. Nicky wants those eggs.
本來維克多的股份可以還清債的
Victor's share would have paid off his debt.
我和他是搭檔 他對我有恩
Victor and I were partners. He was responsible for me.
所以我要對他負責 幫他還債
So now I'm responsible for him and his debt.
胡說八道
Bullshit.
維克多不是死了 是走了
Victor is dead. Just walk away.
- 那不是買賣選擇權   - 哇哦 只是一個...
- That's not an option.   - Oh, wow! This is just...
聽著...
Look...
我們做這份事
We do the job.
尼基的事了后  我得一小部分
Nicky gets his cut, I take a small chunk,
我不用冒什么風險
nowhere near commensurate with my risk,
然后你可以得到可觀的2000萬
and you clear a cool 20 million.
我不明白 只是...
I don't know. This is just...
聽著 我們倆誰都不可以放棄
Look, either we pull this job off flawlessly...
也不可以呼叫韋伯 你也不可以做證人尋求保護
or you call Weber and you ask for witness protection,
那根本就不是你的選擇項
which isn't a choice at all...
因為尼基會找到你并且會干掉你
because Nicky will find you and he will kill you.
不論你走到哪 走多遠
It doesn't matter where you go or how long it takes.
那都是不可改變的事實
That's an unalterable fact.
那好
Well...
我們還是要去偷那該死的彩蛋
Then we steal the fucking eggs, no?
是
Yes.
哦 該死的
Oh, shit.
我們要開始了 退后 謝謝
All right, we are working on it. So back off, please. Thank you.
我覺得他應該叫我的名字
I think he called us a name.
我們不喜歡被侮辱的感覺
We do not like to be insulted.
對
All right.
你知道這枚硬幣的重要性嗎？
Do you know the significance of this coin?
知道
Yeah.
那么僅僅通過事實你就可以知道它是屬于你的了
Then you must know by the mere fact that you have it in your possession,
我無法想像你們倆可以超過我
I cannot assume the two of you will not attempt to double-cross me.
沒有人會超過你 尼基 我們一直在嘗試
Nobody's gonna try to double-cross you, Nicky... We've been trying to...
Ripley  尼基
(Ripley) Nicky...
阿歷克斯 我很遺憾 是的 我們都感到遺憾 不是嗎？
- Alex... I'm so sorry. - Yeah, well, we're all sorry, aren't we?
你沒資格把她帶到這里來
There's no reason for you to bring her here.
你把硬幣給了他
The fact that you gave that coin to him...
讓我覺得我有資格這樣做
tells me there are many reasons
但我只在乎它
but only one I care about.
為什么我們當初不背叛了你呢
Why would we try to betray you?
喲   Ripley  換了是你 也許就背叛了
Well, Ripley, in your case, perhaps
一副被復仇扭曲了的心靈
a misguided sense of revenge.
也許 他天生就是貪婪
His, perhaps, simply greed.
沒關系
It doesn't matter.
我不會給你們兩個機會
I will not take the chance of the two of you...
把我合法的東西帶走然后高價賣出
taking what is rightfully mine and selling it to the highest bidder.
求你了 原諒我 皮特魯維奇先生
Please, excuse me, Mr Petrovich...
求你了 謝謝你
Will you please? Thank you.
哪個法律上說了那些彩蛋是你的
Where is it written that these eggs are yours?
因為它們是屬于我的家族的
Because they belong to my family.
因為我的祖父制造了它們
Because my great-grandfather made them.
是的  Ripley  艾弗真力 皮特魯維奇制造了它們
Yes, Ripley. Evgenly Petrovich made them.
俄語
(Mutters in Russian)
他制造了1917神秘彩蛋
He made the 1917 mystery eggs.
我要得到這些彩蛋
I will have those eggs.
你要為我去找到它們
And you will get them for me.
這就是我把阿歷克斯帶到這里來的原因
That's why I bring Alexandra here.
在你們做你們需要做的事情之時我經營了這個珠寶店
To keep me company while you do what you need to do.
去吧
Go.
誰要是跟蹤我 她就要死
Anyone tries to follow us, she dies.
你們最好乖乖的
You'd better believe she dies.
如果我沒有得到我想要的
If I don't get what I want...
她就要死
she dies.
去吧
Go.
不遠處有個地鐵
There is a subway not far.
就怪你 加布里
Damn you, Gabriel!
我告訴你不能讓她卷入這件事來
I told you not to get her involved.
你告訴我 你告訴我
You told me? You told me?
你和她的父親在她還沒有出生 就已經把她卷入這件事來了
You and her father got her involved even before she was born.
該死，我們明天就行動
Goddamn it: We go tomorrow.
我聽到有聲音
什么聲音？
難道你沒聽到？
沒
建議去查查．完畢
等等
喬治
確實有聲音
上頭說MTA在進行地鐵維修工作
維修？
是的，在地鐵里     把守好崗位 完畢
地下室明白
幾點了？
How much time?
到22點還有3分鐘
Just over three minutes until the 22:00 check.
地下室 22點 檢查完畢
47區 下面是主門
不可能是MTA
我讓喬治去看看
地下室，快來
地下室
去檢查一下地下室的報警
我馬上去
錯誤報警 清除完畢
告訴他們一切正常
通行證 快點 快點
Smart card. Come on... Come on.
走
Let's go.
他在工作
好無聊的
這是怎么了！？
生日快樂 亞瑟
喬治，今天不是我生日
不是嗎？
有人送給亞瑟一份生日蛋糕
今天不是我的生日
我的電話機忘在地下室了 可以進去拿嗎？
喬治，快點  這不是好事
蛋糕真美昧
你應該經常過生日才對
語言重復
(Computer) Rasputin.
(Sergev's recorded voice) Rasputin.
俄語
(Computer) Seventeen.
Seventeen.
俄語
- (Computer) Norway.  - Norway.
(Computer) Cheys Grodny?
Cheys Grodny?
媽的
Fuck.
我不會啊 你知道嗎？
- It wants to know if I'm hungry. - Are you?
俄語
Cheys Grodny?
是的
Nyet.
好的  等等，等等，等等
- All right. - Wait, wait, wait.
走
Go.
停 向右邊
Stop. Go right.
右邊...右邊
Right... Right.
停
Stop.
好的 直接往前走
Good. Straight ahead.
走，走，走
Go, go, go, go, go.
停 頭趴下
Stop. Flatten out. Head down, head down, head down.
好的，現在左移
Okay, now diagonally left.
左移
Diagonally to the left.
繼續...左邊
Keep going... Left.
你的手，看著你的手
Get your arm in. No arms!
趴下
- Flat. Down. - Holy shit.
Okay, straight ahead.
好的．筆直走
走
Go, go, go, go, go.
Go, go.
停 停
Stop. Stop.
裝備
Deploy.
快點
Hurry.
停 停 趴下 趴下
Stop. Stop. Flat. Flat.
好的 快點
Okay, hurry.
盡快
Ouick as you can.
好的
Good.
成功了 走！
It's working. Let's go!
(Drilling)
好了 好了 好了
Hold it, hold it, hold it!
換一個 好的 我看看
- Lead. - Okay... Let's take a look.
何時？  該死
When? Shit!
好的，我馬上到
All right, sit tight. We're on our way.
是的，馬上來
Yes, I owe you.
快準備人手
They're havin ' a sale at Romanov.
長官
Sir?
一切都在掌握中
That was my plant. Unexplained alarm went off about an hour ago.
現在給我準備好需要的
I want all available units in the garage now.
沃迪和麥克，他們會和我們會聚的
Vouti and Michaels, have them meet us at the staging area.
是的，長官   現在輪到我了
- Yes, sir. - Now it's my turn.
很好
We're good.
好了
All right.
慢點．慢點…
Easy, easy, easy, easy, easy.
現在你來 好的
- You're on. - All right.
深點 是嗎？
- (Ripley) A little more. - Ready?
是的，再深點
Come on, a little more.
Come on. More, more, more.
再深點，深點 停！好了…就是這樣
More, more, more. Stop! Okay... Right there.
到位 好的
- All right. - Okay.
One.
不是
No.
Two.
不是…3
No... Three.
不是…4
No... Four.
對了
Hold it! That's it.
4，1...
Four, one.
不是…4，2
No... Four, two.
不是…4，3
No... Four, three.
不是…4，4
No... Four, four.
不是…4，5
No... Four, five.
對了
- Bingo. - (Siren)
- 快點．全速前進    - 知道嗎？
- Go, go, go! Let's go!    - Yes, sir.
是的 是的
Sometime tonight. How about it?
- 好了    - 好了
- All right. - All right.
4，5，6，1，2.
Four, five, six, one, two.
繼續．繼續
Got it. Got it.
4，5，6，1，2，3.
Four, five, six, one, two, three.
不對
No.
4，5，6，1，2，4.
Four, five, six, one, two, four.
不對…1
No... One.
不對
No.
2，5…不對
Two, five... No.
該死
Damn it.
4，5，6，1，2，6.
Four, five, six, one, two, six.
- 成功了   - 好的
- Bingo.   - Okay.
好的
Okay.
4，5，6，1...
Four, five, six, one...
2，6         1...
two, six,       one.
1     快點
One.     Come on.
快點 他媽的你在干什么？
Come on. What the fuck are you doing?
我試試看
Improvising.
該死的
Shit.
- Take this shit off.    - Careful.
- 真的是    - 小心
- 快點     - 要抓住這個家伙
- (Siren)- Come on.    - Move around this guy.
要把他們一網打盡 快點 全速前進
Move those guys out of the way. Come on! Go through the lights!
就是這里
(Ripley) There.
嗯
Hmm.
應該有兩個盒子的
There should be two of these boxes.
對
All right.
好
Okay.
- 你干什么    - 把盒子給我
- What're you doing?    - Give me the box.
- 加布里 別這樣    - 把盒子給我
- Gabriel, don't do this.    - Give me the box.
什么 你想要更多的錢 天啊 你看看你周圍 想要多少拿多少
What, you want more money? Hell... look around you. Take what you want.
閉嘴 把盒子給我
Just, shut up and give me the box.
那阿歷克斯怎么辦 尼基會殺了她的 你知道的
What about Alex? Nicky will kill her. You know that.
我再說最后一次
I will ask you one more time.
你為什么要這樣做？
- Why are you doing this? - (Sighs)
我是一個警察    在邁阿密潛伏了十年
I'm a cop...    In Miami for the last ten years.
是韋伯派我來的    就是為了找你
Weber requested me.    Just for you.
所以你是個警察 你想要抓我 來吧
So you're a cop. You wanna arrest me? Go ahead.
我要到哪里去
Where am I gonna go?
一分鐘之后地下室的門會自動關上 我們都會被困住
But in one minute that vault door's gonna lock and we'll be stuck in here...
阿歷克斯就要死
and Alex is gonna be dead.
我不相信你這種卑鄙小人
I can't believe you're such a contemptible human being...
你連她都會利用然后殺了她
that you would use her like that and then just kill her...
你會作繭自縛的
cos you might as well be pulling the trigger yourself.
送掉 Keith   Ripley 的性命
Simply to bag the great Keith Ripley.
你會后悔的 兔崽子
You sorry, sick motherfucker.
你只有30秒了 我怎樣找到尼基
- You got 30 seconds. - How do I find Nicky?
電話號碼在我口袋里
Phone number in my pocket.
給我 還有彩蛋
Give it to me... and the eggs.
- 你想讓她活著還是死掉     - 你呢
- Do you want her alive or not?     - Do you?
10秒了
Ten seconds.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
同志們 到地下密室去
Underground, boys.
快點 行動
All right, let's move! Come on!
監控室呼叫頂層，完畢
喬治
柏格達，立刻檢查電梯
聽我說 我是警官
I'm a police officer! Listen to me.
地下室有一個竊賊被鎖住了
There is a thief locked in your inner vault.
警衛在地下密室
The guard is in the basement closet.
快 快 快
Move, move, move, move, move!
快點
Now! Move! Come on!
叫他們把槍放下
Tell them to put their weapons down now.
馬上
Now!
0K     好
Okay.     Fine.
放下
Put them down
馬上
Now!
俄語
(Speaks Russian)
踢開　快
Kick them. Now!
你想怎么樣
What do you want?
讓我從前門走出去 我就放了他
You let me out the front door so I can rejoin my unit.
他們包圍了四周
They have the building surrounded.
這時 你們下樓 會發現竊賊和他的同伙
Meantime, you go downstairs, you find your thief and your comrade.
明白了嗎  那扇門會報警的
- You understand? - That door is alarmed.
你有問題了 我們來解決它
You have a problem, solve it.
別逼我 我會殺了他
Do not make me shoot this man, please.
警報晌
(Alarm rings)
把槍放下 我們是警察
- Put down your weapons. - We are police!
是嗎 今晚怎么每個人都是警察啊
Yeah? Everybody's police tonight.
喂
(Nlcky) Hello?
嘿 我手上有你想要的東西  不，就是我
Hey, I have what you want.  No, it's just me.
我們談談吧 我有個建議
Can we talk? I have a proposition for you.
她在哪？
Where is she?
不許動 他盒子后面有槍
Do not move. He has a gun behind the box.
他媽的
Bad boy.
把盒子給我 然后把你的武器交給安德雷
Give me the box and give Andrei your weapon, please.
我們可不想惹上麻煩事
We don't wish trouble here.
不 不 不 你不明白的
No, no, no. You don't understand.
你放她走 我就把盒子給你
You let her go, then I'll give you the box.
明白嗎 如果我打碎了這個盒子
You see, if I fire through this box,
大家都什么都沒了
which I have no problem doing what so ever,
尼基不會高興的
Nicky's not gonna be very happy.
那我們都要完蛋了
Then we are all expendable.
你應該明白我的意思
If you understand the meaning of the word.
把盒子打開
Open the box.
把槍放下 把槍放下
Lower the gun. Lower the gun.
放下
Lower it.
好
Okay.
你還好吧 嗯 我很好 謝謝
- Are you all right? - Yeah. I'm just lovely. Thanks.
你走
You go.
把盒子給我
Give me the box.
上車 為什么
- Get in. - Why?
尼基要見你
Nicky wants too see you.
把你的槍給我
Give me your weapon.
我們沒事 對嗎
We're fine, right?
你們憑什么拘留我們
Where do you get off detaining us?
我向你們道歉 韋伯警長
My apologies, Lieutenant Weber.
我的手下們很困惑
My security were, understandably, confused.
請跟謝爾蓋耶夫到地下室
Please go with Mr. Sergeev down to the vault.
我們有你想要的
We have what you want. Please.
另外一個人呢 沒有別人了 就是他
- Where's the other one? - Nobody else. Just him.
我的人到哪里去了？
Where the hell's my man?
警長 那是你的私事 不關我的事
Lieutenant, your personal life, none of my business.
我很抱歉把你帶到這來
I apologise for bringing you here...
但是我得確保我放你走之前彩蛋不是贗品
but I had to be sure the eggs were genuine before I let you go.
你太不令人信任了 皮特魯維奇
Your lack of trust is really depressing, Mr. Petrovich.
我說話算數
I'm a man of my word.
她現在應該跟她的教父在一起了
She should be with her godfather now.
等著瞧吧
Let's see.
你介意嗎？   不  打吧
- Do you mind? - Sure... Call.
我
Yeah.
喂 是 你在哪？
- Hello? - Hey. Where are you?
我在監獄里 我要見你
I'm at the jail. I had to see him.
他怎么樣
How is he?
你覺得呢
(Sighs) Well, how do you think he is?
我別無選擇 阿歷克斯
I had no choice, Alex.
大家都別無選擇
No one had a choice.
還記得嗎 我告訴過你 我們誰都不能給什么承諾
Remember? I told you. Neither one of us could promise a thing.
聽著 承諾只是過眼云煙
Listen, promises blow away in the wind.
但感覺卻是真實的
But feelings are real.
我知道 有時感覺也會騙人
And I need to know were the feelings lies, too?
聽我說 聽我說 我的意思是
Listen, listen. What I mean is...
你是真的嗎
are we real?
我要走了 加布里 晚安 等等 別走
- I've gotta go, Gabriel. Good night. - Walt Don't go
喂
Hold...
你滿意了？
Are you satisfied?
看了嗎？
Did you see them?
我們根本沒時間看　　你看
- Actually, we were in a hurry. - Look.
他們只是一些
They are simply...
木頭
wood?
天啊 只是些木頭
- Oh, my God: - Simply wood?
是1917年的 加布里
It was 1917, Gabriel.
俄國 那時候人們都在挨餓
Russia. People were starving.
當時沒有珠寶和祖傳留下來
There were no jewels, no diamonds left.
沒指望了
No hope.
然而女皇的兒媳還是要彩蛋
Yet Czarina Alexandra had to have her eggs.
也許你就能明白為什么那時候爆發了革命
Perhaps you understand why we had a revolution.
人們需要一種信仰
People needed to believe in something.
把他帶回去
Take him home.
加布里
Gabriel.
我知道他們是怎么說我的 但我不是殺手
I know what they say about me but I'm not a killer.
一個卑微的移民
Merely a humble immigrant.
跟你一樣
Probably much like you.
我不這樣想 皮特魯維奇先生
I don't think so, Mr. Petrovich.
你跟我一點都不像
You're not like me at all.
很好 謝謝 我們找到皮特魯維奇了
Excellent. Thanks. We've got Petrovich.
斯尼奇叫他進來 通過這段時間的尋找 你知道她到底在哪了嗎
Snitch called it in. After all this time looking for him, you know where he was?
我肯定你會告訴我們的
I'm sure you'll tell us.
躺在木地板上看日出
On the boardwalk, watchin ' the sun come up.
他就要出現了 我馬上回來
He's coming in now. I'll be right back.
是的 我可不依靠那些所謂的職業手
Yeah, what I didn't count on was that a so-called professional...
都是一些沒有什么本事的人
would be manipulated by a chick.
你在邁阿密是哪一類警察
What kind of cops do they make in Miami?
好的那種 韋伯 好的那種
Good ones, Weber. Good ones.
我不明白
I don't get it.
這么多年了，你還能保證你還是你嗎？
All these years in that world. How do you let an asset use you?
一些事情 改變了
Sometimes things... change.
事情改變了？ 比如“我站在哪一邊”改變了？
Things change? Like, "which side am I on" change?
Ripley ，他是誰 是你最好的朋友？
Ripley, what is he, your best friend now?
事實上，我想比你更好
Actually, a better friend than you.
嗯，我知道了，我是混蛋
Ah, I get it. I'm the asshole.
你想告訴我你是個好人…
You're gonna tell me what a good guy he is...
你想控制這個事態？
or how he got caught up in a situation he couldn't control,
自己的女兒把他爸爸逮捕了
or how the sins of the father shouldn't rest on the daughter?
告訴我事情改變了？
Give me something better than, "things change".
如果我是你，我也會這么做的 我能給你的只有真相
All I can give you is the truth.
噢，媽的 滾回邁阿密 媽的 回到邁阿密去，馬丁
Oh, fuck it. Go back to Miami, Martin.
如果你上司給我報告 那你就有事做了
When your superiors get my report, you'll be lucky if you have a job.
我知道
We'll see.
嘿，說說有關 Ripley 的事
Hey, say anything you want about Ripley...
沒有什么可以改變的 最后我會抓到他的
but nothing changes the fact that I finally got him.
雖然目前他在監獄 他會變得很富有的
Now when he leaves prison, he'll be leaving in a pine box.
讓我們去見見帕奇先生
Let's go see Mr. Petrovich.
不
No.
那不是尼基 帕奇
- That's not Nicky Petrovich. - What?
不是他
Not him.
看看，我已經確認是他 他就是尼基 帕奇
Look, man, Organised Crime confirmed it. That's Nicky Petrovich.
好，我不在乎那是不是他
Well, I don't care. That's not him.
我在那，還記得嗎？
I was there, remember?
不是這樣的情況，長官
There's no case here.
什么？ 不是這樣的 你真的認為我們信得過他？
- What? Of course there's a case. - You really think I'll put him on the stand?
一個潛伏在邁阿密的警察，他是否還在職呢？
An undercover Miami cop who may or may not be legit?
不需要了 真麻煩
- No offence. - None taken.
一個臥底警察應該遵守上級命令 隨時準備著…
A cop who's the centrepiece of a botched undercover operation...
停止工作的
that was officially ordered stopped?
我不想讓局里不安，特別是在你的辦公室里
I won't embarrass the Bureau, much less your department,
就是轉到那俄羅斯販毒的地方
which accepted tons of money and equipment from the Russian Mafia.
那寶物呢？ 那個該死的被偷的俄羅斯寶物呢？
What about Romanov's? What about the goddamn stolen treasures of Russia?
那韋伯呢？
What about it, Weber?
當Zykov發現 Ripley 在寶庫里的時候
When Zykov found Ripley in the vault,
當你進去的時候，他已經都清理完了
he had everything cleared out before you could get in.
我有個請求
(Ripley) I have a proposltlon for you.
羅曼不可能去控訴 Ripley 的
There's no way Romanov's will press charges against Ripley.
這會讓他們之前干的事情都包不住的
Cos they can never admit that the eggs or anything else ever existed.
我們只能假設馬丁探員
So we can't even prove that Detective Martin and Ripley.
偷走了所有東西
stole even a goddamn dime.
但是你們得殺死馬克
But you must have mug shots.
俄羅斯人這沒有同伙
Russian Mafia, known associates, something.
就是他
That's him.
那就是尼基 帕奇
That's Nicky Petrovich.
馬丁，是他？…
- Detective Martin... - Yeah?
那就開始吧
That's Victor Korolenko.
馬上就會死了
Presumed dead.
我們找不到尸體
We just never found the body.
找不到的…
You never will...
上尉
Lieutenant.
韋伯
Weber.
什么？
What?
在法官面前展示出來 然后宣判無罪了
His lawyer got him in front of a judge on an expedited bail hearing.
他剛走了
Then he just walked.
- 那是誰？    - 是誰？
- Who was it?    - Who was what?
- 律師     - 你以為律師是誰？
- The lawyer.    - Who the fuck do you think?
阿歷克斯
Alex. Korolenko.
你不能保證我一些事情…
You can't promise me anything so...
可能我們不應該去做的
maybe we shouldn't even try.
爸爸（俄語）
- Papa. - (Speaks Russian)
俄語 我們走吧
(Alex speaks Russian) Shall we go?
俄語
(Speaking Russian)
嗯？
Yeah?
不辭而別是不對的…
(Ripley) Didn't wanna leave without saylng goodbye...
你好吧
I owe you one Gaby.
這單邊的協議可不是好玩的
The real Nicky Petrovich is the one Zykov is funnelling the contraband through.
謝謝你，我不會忘記的
Thank you, but Zykov and Petrovich have gone to ground.
- 你跳迪斯高吧     - 玫瑰舞廳？
- Check out a disco called...    - Riga Rose?
嗯，我想你很熟悉那地方的
Ahh, I see you're famliar with the territory.
好的…我是個警察，別忘記了
Well... I am a cop, remember?
我時刻都不會忘記的
I never forgot it for a second.
你什么時候知道的？
When did you know?
我在邁阿密之前就知道了
I knew you were comlng up from Miaml before you did Gaby.
去看看韋伯和我…
See Weber and I...
當然，我們分享了相同的資訊
Well, let's just say we share the same sources
只是我有更多的報酬
only I pay better.
長官．我們要走了
Sir, we're good to go.
那你怎么幫助 Ripley 的？
So why the help Ripley?
可能是感覺有罪惡感？
Maybe feeling guilty?
我的辭匯里沒有罪惡
Guilt's not even in my vocabulary.
我只希望你從不同角度看事情
I was just hoping you'd see things differently.
我和你合作可以完成任何事
Together you and I could do anything.
是的．我相信
Yeah. I believe we did.
如果你有興趣，我稍后聯系你吧
I'll get in touch later on, if you're interested.
同時，我有東西給你準備著
Meanwhile, I've got to keep an appointment with a man...
豐厚的獎賞
who's gonna pay dearly for something...
在地下室做好開鎖 是他是那樣說的
he's got to keep locked in his basement just to say it's his.
親愛的．再見 等等．等等
- Good hunting, Gaby. - Wait, wait, wait!
讓我跟她說一會
Let me talk to her. Just for a second.
是他？  你想她會去哪里嗎？
- That's him? - What makes you think she's going anywhere?
她不會犯什么錯誤的
She didn't commit any crime.
她只是以其人之道還治其人之身
She just lied to someone who was lying to her.
你會更好的
You be good.
我試試吧． Keith 叔叔
I'll try, Uncle Keith.
我想我的合法職業結束了
Although I suspect my legal career just ended.
謝天謝地
Thank God.
我說你每天晚上都會來這里…
You come in here every night and every night I tell you...
聽起來我什么都不知道
I don't know shit from this Petrovich.
俄語
(Speaks Russian)
這是酒吧，朋友
This is a nightclub, my friend.
你知道我在想什么？
You know what I think?
我想你應該好好放松下自己了  你知道我在說什么吧
I think you need to check out the action and get your ass laid.  You know what I'm saying
是的 老兄
Yeah.  dude?
好好享受吧
Find yourself a chick.
伏特加
Vodka. (Speaks Russian)
俄語
叫酒的意思
噢
Zakuska?
你餓了？
Russian hors d'eurvres to coat the stomach.
我想是吧
Oh.
我認為你是不喝酒的
Will my stomach need coating? -
你在想事情
I hope so.
和這事情沒有關系
I thought you didn't drink.
我想這不是我們該談論的事情
You thought a lot of things,but I believe I mentioned something about making assumptions.
或許這是我們應該擺脫的     現在
Maybe that's a concept we should get rid of.    Immediately.
我叫馬丁
My name is Gabriel Martin.
來自邁阿密
I'm from Miami.
實際上我是一個律師 但事務所關門了
I was actually looking for a lawyer but the office was closed.
所以...
So...
我來了這里
I came here.
好的
Okay.
我是阿歷克斯 格羅林科
My name is Alexandra Korolenko...
來自圣彼德堡
and I come from St. Petersburg.
一個海港邊
By way of Little Odessa.
我
And...
我喜歡跳舞
I love to dance.
所以…我來這里
So... I came here tonight.
你想和我跳舞嗎？
Do you wanna dance with me?
好
Yeah.
我非常愿意
I'm willing to make a fool of myself.
我也一樣
Me too.
阿歷克斯   嗯？
- Alex... - Yeah?
那晚你從島上來
That night when I called you from... huh, Coney Island
你還沒有回答我的問題
you never answered my question.
什么問題？
Which one?
我想…我想知道…
I wanted... I want to know...
你不會是說謊吧？
Was it all lies?
那不管用的
Not the part that matters.
Let's make a promlse you and me
Let's just be honest
We're gonna run
那是真的
That was true.
那是真實的感受
That was real. I felt that.
真的 確實是真的
That was real. That was real. Finally.
Beyond the clouds over the mountains
We'll run away on roads that are empty
Lights from the airfield shining upon you
Nothing can stop us
Not now I love you
They're not gonna get us
Nothing can stop us
Not now I love you
They're not gonna get us
We'll run away keep everything simple
Night wlll come down our guardian angel
We rush ahead the crossroads are empty
Our spirits rise
They're not gonna get us
My love for you always forever
Just you and me
All else is nothing
Not going back
Not going back there
They don't understand
They don't understand us
Not gonna get us
They're not gonna get us
Nothing can stop us
Not now I love you
They're not gonna get us
Nothing can stop us
Not now I love you
They're not gonna get us
Not gonna get us not gonna get us
Not gonna get us